hello everyone welcome back to today's another new tutorial series so today we are going to explore
for how to create the database in the MongoDB for the database in MongoDB our container for the
collection which will turn as the container for the document okay so now simply explain for the
MongoDB create DB okay so first of all here creating a database in MongoDB which is straightforward
and can be done using the use command in the MongoDB shell and just explore for how it works for
the sample okay so first of all here I can just go for use the new coordinator for the MongoDB and now
I can just go for here the compass inside this here and just go the new collection and here
first of all here the local host ID so now here simply create the click for with this connect okay
so here perfectly open for the local host for this and now here I can create for this is the
new database okay so you can see this the plus icon the 3 database okay so first of all here I
can just click and here simply create a new database suppose here I can just type this is the
use okay and now here I can also create the collections name for my data base okay so here simply create
for my database and now just for now you click for this create button and now perfectly create for
the new database okay so now just click and here the completely create for the new database and now
then here I can just go here you can see just go to the database and now first of all the
that test because I can just go to the previous test of purpose and here I can click for this
new database and this is the admin for this MongoDB and this the block and the bookstore for the
config and the config for then this data DB and now here I can just newly create for the database
and the collection name for here in my database okay it's simply create for in this example
this data query and here I can just go for this index inside so it's the regular for the
documentation process and navigation and also the schema then the validation and also
more option for provide for the MongoDB numbers and here just use for simply
just go here use the inside and use for the database and you can choose for here create for
another collection okay so here is completely used for this and you can simply just choose for
another database just create now so you can choose here so just type so now first of all here
I can just remove all this test DB also here I can create for now you can just remove this test
DB so type the test to confirm collection so now here I can just type this drop for this test
DB so type okay so now the ST simply just type for the DB okay so now drop for this database
and it is part to be dropped okay so here I can use for another create collection so here I can
use for the same name so first of all I can start this test for the DB and create here the
collections name so it's not the collection and there I can just create first of all the
database okay so just go here and first of all simply I can create for the test DB
it's not now so this is a test DB and here use for the test DB and suppose like
that data okay so now here create the database and you can see here perfectly created for this
database okay so first I can stay for this database and this data for the collection
for that data okay so here completely done and here I have perfectly created for the new
database for in this session and there you have it perfectly of all view of the
computing database in the MongoDB for some practical example I hope you perfectly understand
this tutorial so stay tuned for more MongoDB tips and tricks okay so thank you for
for watching and happy coding for the data query, okay?